## **ERIC SAI KIT CHEUNG**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER REACT & REDUX, JAVASCRIPT, RUBY ON RAILS, MERN, POSTGRESQL

#### **PROFILE**

I've owned and operated a food business in Hawaii & Brooklyn, selfpublished a fiction novel, and am now a Full-stack Developer specializing in React & Redux, JavaScript, and Ruby & Rails.

I love to build aesthetically pleasing projects, find creative solutions to problems, and am an avid food adventurer & cat instagram follower.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **FLATIRON SCHOOL**

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT FEBRUARY 2020 – JUNE 2020

React & Redux, JavaScript, Ruby & Rails, SQL and PostgreSQL

#### SOKA UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA BACHELOR OF ARTS AUGUST 2008 – MAY 2012

Social Behavioral Sciences - 3.8 GPA

### CONTACT



Eric. Saik it. Cheung@gmail.com



646.637.1808



https://ericskcheung.com



www.linkedin.com/in/eric-sk-cheung



erock\_esquire

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### HIES INC • FRONT-END DEVELOPER • JULY 2020 - AUGUST 2020

Designed & rebuilt HIES company website using React JS & Redux, & SASS/SCSS.

- **Redesigned** & built entire HIES company website to be modern, manageable, and business & user-friendly. Utilized React Router for URL address routing.
- **Incorporated** PIXI.js to create realistic moving water effect on hero image. Recreated original hero image using Adobe Photoshop for higher resolution.
- **Organized** over 20 company services into 4 manageable categories, composed descriptions for each service, and added search feature for services.

## **FLATIRON PROJECT: CURBALERT • FULL STACK DEVELOPER •**JUNE 2020

Created React JS & Redux, Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to post images & details of unwanted items on street onto a public map.

- **Engineered** codebase synchronizing Geolocation & Google Geocode API to obtain user coordinates used to incorporate Google Directions API, allowing users to see directions and distance to items.
- **Collaborated** functionality between AWS S3 Cloud & Rails Active Storage to store user post images on cloud bucket through Rails back-end API.

## **FLATIRON PROJECT: HANGOUTS •** FULL STACK DEVELOPER • MAY 2020

Created React JS, Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web app able to plan meetups at location calculated to be mutually close distance between all participants.

- **Architected** a RESTful Rails back-end call to YELP Search API to provide restaurant suggestions at user current coordinates and requested coordinates, before plotting to Leaflet API map.
- **Composed** function to calculate a midpoint location between groups of users from coordinate data retrieved by Geolocation & Google Geocode API.

# **BANZAI PHRESH •** OWNER/SOLE PROPRIETOR • APRIL 2016 – JUNE 2018

Owned & operated restaurants at two locations. Oversaw restaurant design, customer service, cooking, financials, and logistical operation of the business.

- Ala Moana Mall Honolulu, Hl. We averaged 100 customers a day, maintained a 30% profit margin, with 4.5 star reviews on Yelp.
- Smorgasburg Market Brooklyn, NY. We averaged 200 customers a day and maintained a 25% profit margin.
- **Resolved** logistical problems such as strict time management, division of labor, inventory tracking & ordering deadlines, and maintaining quality of service & food.

#### KINGS OF FORTUNE • AUTHOR/WRITER • 2014

Self-published an action/adventure fiction novel.

• **Awarded** 5 of 5 stars on San Francisco Book Review, 4 of 5 stars on Portland Book Review, and featured review on Kirkus magazine.